Deepak Maram

Research

I am broadly interested in computer security and applied cryptography. My recent focus has largely been around decentralized identity. My research has led to direct industry adoption. DECO is licensed from Cornell by Chainlink. ZkAttest is implemented and maintained by Cloudflare. CHURP is on Oasis Labs product road map.

Education

2018-present Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science.

Cornell University, USA Advisor: Ari Juels, GPA: 3.71/4

2012-16 B.Tech in Computer Science with Honors.

Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay, India

GPA: 8.91/10

Industry Experience

2020 Cryptography Research Engineer Internship, Cloudflare, Remote.

Devised a privacy-preserving, usable alternative to CAPTCHA using WebAuthn (Web Authentication) as the base layer with a ring-signature scheme as an anonymity layer. Designed a zero knowledge Σ -protocol and prototyped it in TypeScript.

2021 Research Engineer, Offchain Labs (Arbitrum), Remote.

Worked on minimizing delay-induced negative externalities in optimistic rollups. Designed an insurance token to hedge against protocol delays, solutions to linear delay attacks.

Programming Experience

Languages C++ (4000 lines), Python (3000 lines), Java (3000 lines), JavaScript (1000 lines), Rust (500 lines)

Selected Research Projects

- 2022 Formal study and design of new multi-factor authentication mechanisms.
 - D. Maram, I. Eyal, M. Kelkar. Ongoing.
- 2021-22 GoAT: File Geolocation via Anchor Timestamping, github.
 - D. Maram, I. Bentov, M. Kelkar, A. Juels. In submission.
- 2020-21 CanDID: Can-Do Decentralized Identity with Legacy Compatibility, Sybil-Resistance, and Accountability, candid.id.
 - D. Maram, H. Malvai, F. Zhang, N. Jean-Louis, A. Frolov, T. Kell, T. Lobban, C. Moy, A. Juels, and A. Miller. In IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (S&P) 2021.
 - 2020 ZkAttest: Ring and Group Signatures for existing ECDSA keys, github. A. Faz-Hernandez, W. Ladd, D. Maram. In Selected Areas in Cryptography (SAC) 2021.
- 2019-20 DECO: Liberating Web Data Using Decentralized Oracles, deco.works. F. Zhang, D. Maram, H. Malvai, S. Goldfeder, and A. Juels. In Proceedings of the 2020 ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS).

2018-19 CHURP: Dynamic-committee Proactive Secret Sharing, *churp.io*.

D. Maram, F. Zhang, L. Wang, A. Low, Y. Zhang, A. Juels, and D. Song. *In Proceedings of the 2019 ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS)*.

Honors / Awards

- 2018 Awarded University Fellowship by Cornell University
- 2012 Secured All India Rank 12 in IIT-JEE out of 500,000 students
- 2012 Secured All India Rank 36 in AIEEE out of 11,00,000 students
- 2012 Recipient of KVPY scholarship and attended VIJYOSHI Camp
- 2011 Awarded merit certificate for being in top 1% in National Standard Examination Astronomy

Posters / Talks

2021 GoAT: File Geolocation via Anchor Timestamping.

Presented our work at the Protocol Labs Research Seminar Series, 2021.

Presented our work at the Initiative for Cryptocurrencies and Contracts (IC3) Retreat, 2021

2020-21 CanDID: A Decentralized Identity System.

Presented our work at the IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (S&P), 2021.

Presented our work at the Novi Reserach Seminar, 2021.

Presented our work at the Hyperledger Identity Working Group, 2020.

Presented our work at the 31st Internet Identity Workshop, 2020.

Presented our work at the Travel Rule Information Sharing Architecture Forum, 2020.

2019 CHURP: Dynamic-committee Proactive Secret Sharing.

Presented our work at the ACM conference on Computer and Communication Security (CCS), London

Gave a talk at the Initiative for Cryptocurrencies and Contracts (IC3) Winter Retreat, Interlaken.

Graduate Course Work

Security & Privacy Technologies, Privacy in the Digital Age, Cryptocurrency and Smart Contracts, Advanced Programming Languages, Advanced Operating Systems, Intro to Computer Vision, Computational Ring Theory (UG), Graph Theory (UG)

Media Coverage

- Aug 29, 2020 Forbes, "Chainlinks New Acquisition From Cornell University Could Transform Blockchain For Good".
- Aug 29, 2020 CoinDesk, "Chainlink Acquires Blockchain Oracle Solution From Cornell University".
- Mar 30, 2019 MIT Tech Review China, "The whereabouts of 4 million bitcoins worldwide are missing".

Service / Extra-curriculars

- 2021-22 Acted as a Teaching Assistant for the courses: CS5433: Blockchains, Cryptocurrencies, and Smart Contracts, CS5435: Security and Privacy Concepts in the Wild.
- 2019-20 Served as the treasurer of PhD student organization At Cornell Tech (PACT)
 - 2014 Awared first prize at the XLR8 competition for designing a Wireless Controlled Bot
- 2003-07 Won first prize in several district-level chess competitions and participated in state-level competitions